you and your friend need to ace Friday's
你和你的朋友需要在周五的比赛中取得好成绩
exam to avoid summer classes
避免暑期班的考试
and after a week of studying
经过一周的学习
you both feel confident that you pulled it off
你们俩都觉得自己成功了
but when you get your grades back
但等你的成绩回来了
they're much lower than the two of you expected
它们比你们两个预期的要低得多
you're devastated  however
然而，你被摧毁了
your friend doesn't seem too bothered
你的朋友似乎不太在意
and it's making you wonder why you can't
这让你想知道为什么你不能
shake this off like they can
像他们一样摆脱这一切
but should you really be trying
但你真的应该尝试
to look on the bright side
看到光明的一面
and is controlling our emotions
控制我们的情绪
even possible in the first place
甚至一开始就有可能
the answer to the last question is a definitive yes
最后一个问题的答案是肯定的
there are numerous strategies
有许多策略
for regulating our emotions
调节我们的情绪
and one framework to understand these
和一个框架来理解这些
techniques is called the process model
技术称为过程模型
psychologists use this tool to identify where and how
心理学家使用这个工具来确定在哪里以及如何
to intervene in the process that forms our emotions
干预形成我们情感的过程
that process has four steps  first
这个过程首先有四个步骤
we enter a situation
我们进入一个情境
real or imagined
真实的或想象的
and that draws our attention
这引起了我们的注意
then we evaluate or appraise the situation
然后我们评估或评估情况
and whether it helps or hinders our goals
以及它是否有助于或阻碍我们的目标
finally  this appraisal leads to a set
最后这个评估得出一套
of changes in how we feel
我们感觉的变化
think and behave
思考和行动
known as an emotional response
被称为情绪反应
each step of this process offers an opportunity to
这个过程的每一步都提供了一个机会
consciously intervene and change our emotions
有意识地干预和改变我们的情绪
and the process model outlines what
过程模型概述了什么
strategies we might try at each phase
我们在每个阶段可能尝试的策略
to see this in action
看到这个在行动
let's imagine you've been invited to the same party
假设你被邀请参加同一个派对
as your least favorite ex and their new partner
作为你最不喜欢的前任和他们的新搭档
your first strategy could be avoiding the
你的第一个策略可能是避免
situation altogether by skipping the party
完全跳过派对的情况
but if you do attend
但是如果你真的参加了
you could also try modifying the situation by
您也可以尝试通过以下方式改变情况
choosing not to interact with your ex
选择不与前任交往
if that's proving difficult
如果这证明很困难
you might want to shift your attention
你最好转移一下注意力
maybe by playing a game with your friends
也许和你的朋友玩个游戏
rather than focusing on your ex's new partner
而不是关注你前任的新搭档
another option would be to
另一个选择是
re evaluate how you think about the situation
重新评估你对形势的看法
after seriously reappraising things
在认真重新评估事情之后
you might realize that you don't
你可能会意识到你没有
care who your ex dates
关心你的前任和谁约会
if none of these strategies work
如果这些策略都不起作用
you can always try tempering your
你可以试着回火你的
emotional response after the fact
事后情绪反应
but this can be tricky
但这可能很棘手
many of the easiest ways to do this
许多最简单的方法来做到这一点
like hiding your emotions or trying to
比如隐藏你的情绪或试图
change them with recreational drugs
用消遣性药物改变它们
generally lead to more negative feelings
通常会导致更多的负面情绪
and health concerns in the long term
和长期的健康问题
more sustainable strategies here
更可持续的策略
include going for a long walk
包括去散步
taking slow deep breaths
慢慢地深呼吸
or talking with someone in your support system
或者与您的支持系统中的人交谈
while using all these strategies well takes practice
虽然使用所有这些策略需要练习
learning to notice your emotions and reflect on
学会注意你的情绪并反思
where they're coming from is half the battle
他们来自哪里是成功的一半
and once you've truly internalized that
一旦你真正内化了它
you can regulate your emotions
你可以调节你的情绪
doing so becomes much easier
这样做变得容易多了
but should you use these techniques to
但是你应该使用这些技术来
constantly maintain a good mood
不断保持好心情
that answer depends on how you
这个答案取决于你如何
define what makes a mood good
定义什么让心情好
it's tempting to think we should always
很容易认为我们应该永远
try to avoid sadness and frustration
尽量避免悲伤和沮丧
but no emotion is inherently good or bad
但没有一种情绪是天生的好坏
they're either helpful or unhelpful
它们要么有帮助，要么没有帮助
depending on the situation
视情况而定
for example  if a friend is telling you
例如，如果一个朋友告诉你
about the loss of a loved one
关于失去亲人的事
feeling and expressing sadness isn't just appropriate
感受和表达悲伤不仅仅是合适的
it can help you empathize and support them
它可以帮助你同情和支持他们
conversely  while it's unhealthy to
相反，虽然这样做不健康
regularly ignore your emotions
经常忽略你的情绪
forcing a smile to get through a one time
强颜欢笑度过一次
annoyance is perfectly reasonable
烦恼是完全合理的
we hear a lot of mixed messages about emotions
我们听到很多关于情绪的混合信息
some pressure us to stay upbeat
有些压力让我们保持乐观
while others tell us to simply
而其他人告诉我们
take our emotions as they come
随遇而安
but in reality
但实际上
each person has to find their own balance  so
每个人都要找到自己的平衡所以
if the question is should you always try to be happy
如果问题是你应该一直试着快乐
the answer is no
答案是否定的
studies suggest that people fixated on happiness
研究表明关注幸福的人
often experience secondary negative emotions like
经常经历次生负面情绪，比如
guilt or frustration over being upset
因心烦意乱而感到内疚或沮丧
and disappointment that they don't feel happier
以及他们没有感到更快乐的失望
this doesn't mean you should let
这并不意味着你应该让
sadness or anger take over
悲伤或愤怒占据上风
but strategies like reappraisal can help you
但是像重新评估这样的策略可以帮助你
reevaluate your thoughts about a situation
重新评估你对情况的想法
allowing you to accept that you feel sad
让你接受你感到悲伤
and cultivate hope that things will get better
培养一切都会好起来的希望
if someone told you not to do something
如果有人告诉你不要做某事
would that make you want to do it
这会让你想这么做吗？
learn about what psychologists refer to as the
了解心理学家所说的
Romeo and Juliet effect with this video
罗密欧与朱丽叶效果与此视频
or get more actionable science based
或获得更可操作的基于科学的
advice on how to build character at Ed  Ted
关于如何在Ed Ted培养性格的建议
com forward slash build character
com正斜杠构建字符